Dear, oh dear. It seems he had quite a bit of trouble returning to the capital.
（呂不韋(りょふい)）
やれやれ 都に帰るのも大変だのぅ
But I suppose it's fine now.
（呂不韋）だが まあよいか
Now I'm interested to see what kind of face the king, that has overcome all of this strife, will greet us with.
危うく生き延びた大王が
どんな顔で我らを出迎えてくれるか
見届けるのも また一興
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
（信(しん)）ンンッ！
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Lü Buwei
（幸）
おいおい！ そんなに少しずつ―
Hey, hey!
If you carry stuff, little by little, all carefree like that,
ノコノコ運んでたんじゃ
ラチが明かねえぜ
you're never gonna get anywhere.
Xin
Ow!
あいて…
フン… しょうがねえな
Oh well.
（信）ただいま～っと
I'm back.
He Liao Diao
（貂(てん)）お疲れ　ちょうど
メシができたとこだぞ
Good work! I made us some dinner.
（信）か～っ！ 食った食った
Man, I'm stuffed!
満足満足！ フフッ…
（貂）なんかムカつく
That sure is satisfying!
That sorta pisses me off.
（貂）それにしても 正に平穏
Anyhow... It sure is peaceful.
この間の王宮での戦いが
ウソみたいだ
It feels like the battle at the Royal Palace a few days ago never happened.
信は働いて 少しは稼ぐし―
Now you're working and earning a little income
俺も山菜とか採って
食費 助けてるし
while I go pick edible wild weeds and stuff to help with the food expenses.
なんとか普通にやっていけてるよな
Somehow we're carrying on normally.
うん 普通にやっていけてる
いいよな こういうの
Yeah. Normally...
It's nice... having things like this...
（信）つかの間の休息ってやつだ
A quick break, I guess.
いや だからさ 俺が言ってんのは
普通にやっていけるんだから―
No, what I'm saying is
what we're doing is normal.
別に つかの間にしなくても…
（信のあくび）
Not a quick break or anything...
ハァ… 俺は寝るぜ
I'm goin' to sleep.
（信）貂の言うとおり
普通にやっていけてる
It's just like Diao said.
We're living normally.
俺だって 悪かねえと思ってるさ
Even I don't think this is so bad.
けど
いつまでも こうしちゃいられねえ
But I can't keep going like this forever.
戦に出て 手柄を上げて
将軍への道を進まねえと
I've got to get on the battlefield, build up achievements,
and move forward on my path to general!
オリャー！
My shoulder that got hurt by Zuoci...
左慈(さじ)にやられた肩が
まだ元に戻ってねえ
it's still not back to normal...!
（戸の開く音）
（貂）信！
Xin!
What's wrong, Diao?
どうした？ 貂
お… 俺… 政(せい)に…
（信）政に？
I... From Zheng...
Zheng?!
まだ約束の金もらってねえ！
I never got the money he promised me!
約束の金？
（貂）うん うん
Money... he promised?
（信）ハァ…
（信）びっくりさせんじゃねえ！
Don't scare me like that, dammit!
If you're that mad, then why're you coming with me... Xin?
（貂）あんなに怒ってたのに
なんで ついてくんだよ？ 信
“なんで”って… そりゃ あれだよ
Why? Well... You know.
お前
政にガッツリ金もらうだろう？
You're gonna get lots of money from Zheng, right?
そしたら 帰り道
追い剥ぎとかに襲われねえように
So I thought you might need a bodyguard in case you got robbed on the way back.
用心棒が要るかなみたいな？
That sorta thing.
はは～ん…
（信）えっ？
要するに 政に会いたいってことね
So basically you just wanna see Zheng, right?
W-Who the hell would wanna see that annoying bastard that does nothing but try to act cool all the time?!
だ… 誰が
あんなカッコつけてばっかの―
嫌みな野郎に会いてえもんかよ！
フフッ… ケケケケ～！
（信）待て こら！
Wait, dammit!
（信）
やっぱ 何度見ても でっけえな
Man, no matter how many times I look at this thing, it's huge!
（貂）そりゃ 王宮の門だからな
That's because it's a gate to the Royal Palace.
王さまを守るには
これぐらい でっかくないと
It's gotta be this big in order to protect a king...
お前 大丈夫か？
（貂）何がだよ？
Are you gonna be okay?
What?
この間 王宮ん中で 山の民が
大暴れしたばっかだっつうのに
The Mountain People were running wild in the middle of the Royal Palace just the other day,
do you really think they'll let you in dressed like that?
そんな格好で王宮に入れんのかよ？
フン！ 信に言われたくないよ
You're one to talk!
（門番）待てい！
（信）ほ～らな　まったく…
Halt!
See? Geez...
Who the hell are you?!
（門番）貴様！ 何者だ？
（貂）えっ？ 何者って…
Who am I?
お… 俺の名は…
M-My name is...
He Liao Diao!
河了貂(かりょうてん)なり！
Ao... ao... ao..
（貂）なりなり なりなり なり～…
バッカじゃねえの？
そんなことして王宮に…
Are you an idiot?
They're not gonna let you into the Royal Palace because you're doing somethin' like-
You may enter!
（門番）入ってよし！
（信）えっ？
（貂）どうも！
（信）な… なんだ そりゃ！
Thanks!
What's with that?!
Hey, you! Do a better job gate guarding!
てめえ！
ちゃんと門番の仕事やってんのか？
政に もしものことがあったら
ただじゃおかねえぞ！
They're not gonna let you off the hook if somethin' happens to Zheng!
Thanks.
そんなこと言われても…
Well, regardless...
“かくかくしかじかの者に
王宮の出入りを許す”
His highness specifically gave me the order "There is such and such a person you should allow into the Royal Palace.
“その者の名は河了貂なり”と
大王じきじきのご命令があり
That their name is He Liao Diao".
この人とも思えぬ人相書きが…
And I have this description which doesn't seem like it could be a person...
そ… そうなの？
Is... Is that right?
よう 政！ 元気してっか？
Hey, Zheng!
Doin' okay?
あれ？
あれ？ どうした …の？
Huh? What's... goin' on?
He has returned.
（政）戻ってきたのだ
（信）誰が？
Who did?
The ruler of this country from the shadows.
（政）この秦国を
動かす影の支配者…
King of Qin  Ying Zheng
The chancellor, Lü Buwei.
丞相(じょうしょう)の呂不韋がだ
呂不韋だと？
Lü Buwei...?
呂不韋っていやぁ
Lü Buwei, the man who took advantage of Zheng's young age to do whatever he wanted
政が若いのをいいことに
好き放題やっといて
いざってときにゃ 政を
見殺しにしようとした野郎だろう？
and then tried to leave him to die when he really needed him?
そういうヤツが
いちばん気に食わねえ！
That guy pisses me off more than anyone else!
（信）ちょうど良かったじゃねえか
I guess this is perfect timing...
そいつが
政を助けに来なかったことは―
It's an indisputable fact that that guy didn't come to help Zheng.
紛れもねえ事実だ
それをとがめて 処罰すりゃ―
As punishment for that,
正々堂々
政が この国の王さまってことだ
Zheng is gonna be the fair-and-square official king of this country.
（壁(へき)）
それができれば 何の苦労もない
If we could do that, there would be no problem.
どういう …ことだよ？
What... do you mean?
Bi
*One of Ying Zheng's close aides
対抗勢力だった
竭氏(けつし)一党も―
Even though some of Jie Shi's faction that had opposed him still exists,
残っているとはいえ
その勢力は弱まった
their power has diminished.
もはや朝廷は
呂不韋の勢力一色
The Imperial Court is now almost uniformly behind Lü Buwei.
In that environment, it is not possible for even the king to judge Lü Buwei.
そんな中で呂不韋を裁くことは
いかに王といえども 不可能だ
もし
呂不韋が本気で反乱を起こすなら
If Lü Buwei seriously starts a rebellion,
その力は成蟜(せいきょう)たちの比ではなく
it would be incomparable to Ying Zheng's supporters.
And our forces are exceedingly small.
それに対する我らの力は
極めて小さい
万の軍勢に
10人で立ち向かうようなものだ
It would be like 10 people standing against an army of 10,000.
It ain't the numbers!
（信）数じゃねえ！
（廷臣たち）うん？
戦は数じゃねえ 人だ！
A battle ain't about the numbers.
It's the people!
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）確かに そのとおりだ
You do indeed have a point.
Having fought with you once to regain the throne,
１度 玉座を奪還するために
戦っただけで―
with you having realized that, I believe your intuition is not bad.
そのことに気づいたお前の
勘どころは悪くない… じゃがな 信
But Xin...
Changwenjun
*One of Ying Zheng's close aides
The other side has distantly higher human talent than us as well!
その人材も 向こうが
はるかに上なのだ
What?!
なに？
（政）泣き言は言ってられん
I cannot just sit here and whine!
俺と呂不韋との争いは
もう始まっているのだからな
Because the war between Lü Buwei and I has already begun!
Chancellor, Lord Lü Buwei has arrived!
（廷臣）丞相 呂不韋さまが
到着されました！
（信）
いよいよ 呂不韋ってヤツの登場か
So that Lü Buwei guy's finally showing up?
政を見殺しにしようとしといて
After trying to leave Zheng to die,
今更 どのツラ下げて出てくっか
見届けてやるぜ！
I'd like to see how he can dare show his face here.
何だ？ こいつら…
ものすげえ重圧を感じる
Who are these guys...?
I can feel an incredible pressure coming from them.
I don't believe it.
信じられねえ…
こいつら ひとりひとりが―
Each one of these guys
今まで戦ってきた刺客や兵士とは
比べものにならねえぐれえの―
are releasing an incomparably stronger qi than the assassins and soldiers I've fought so far!
気を放ってやがる
（呂不韋）
まずは ともかく…
First and foremost,
Right Chancellor of the State of Qin   Lü Buwei
I am glad to see that you are safe... your highness.
ご無事で何よりでした
大王さま
声が出ねえ…
I... can't speak.
何だ？ この…
What is this...? This feeling...
丸ごと のみ込まれちまうような
この感じは！
It's like I'm being swallowed whole!
（呂不韋）早速ですが 大王さま
I know this is sudden, but your highness...
こたびの反乱に際して 我らが
救援に駆けつけなかったことを―
At the time of this rebellion...
I am sure you are displeased we did not come as reinforcements.
さぞ ご不快にお思いでしょう
そのご不快は ごもっともです
何しろ…
That dissatisfaction is most natural...
But at any rate,
私は 大王さまが
お亡くなりになればよいと―
I would not have minded it if you had died, your highness.
思っておりましたので
どうなってんだ？
What's going on?
あいつ 政を見殺しにしようと
したって あっさり吐いちまったぞ
This guy just straight-out admitted
he tried to leave Zheng for dead.
これで もう一件落着じゃ…
（昌文君）否…
Is... the whole thing settled now?
No...
先ほども壁が言ったはずだ
Bi told you this before as well.
“今の我々には
呂不韋を裁けない”と
As we are now, we cannot pass judgement on Lü Buwei.
Why...?
なんでだよ？ 裁くも何も―
Able to judge him or not, that guy's after your life, Zheng!
そいつは
お前の命を狙ってるんだぞ 政！
Enough jokes, Chancellor Lu.
冗談は よせ 呂丞相
何か事情があってのことだろう
You bring reasons, do you not?
Wha-?!
そこには
そんなにも差があるのか？ 政
Is there... that big a difference even there... Zheng?
（呂不韋）正に冗談です
Indeed, a joke.
沈んだ空気を和らげようかと
とんだご無礼を
I suppose it was quite a rude way to dissolve the tension in the air.
お許しください 大王さま
Please forgive me, your highness.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦乱の時代といえども
Though it was the Warring States Period,
臣下が王の命を狙うとなれば
異常な事態である
the idea of a retainer seeking to take the life of the king was an abnormal situation.
Before Lü Buwei whom was trying to pass this over,
それを堂々と
闇に葬ろうとする呂不韋を前にして
Zheng, Changwenjun and the others could say nothing.
政も昌文君たちも 何も言えない
両陣営の間に
圧倒的な力の差があることを―
The difference in power between the two camps
如実に表した光景であった
was displayed vividly in this spectacle.
（蔡沢(さいたく)）ヒッヒッヒッ…
茶番は もう済みましたかな？
Has this farce ended...?
It has been quite a long time, your highness...
お久しゅうございます 大王さま
お元気そうで何よりです
I am most happy to see you are well.
Cai Ou? It's been quite some time.
（政）蔡沢か 久しいな
蔡沢？ あの老人が…
Cai Ou? That old man is...?!
知ってんのか？ 壁のあんちゃん
You know him, Brother Bi?
蔡沢さまは
３代前の王 昭王(しょうおう)の時代に―
Lord Cai Ou served as chancellor in the age of King Zhao.
丞相を務められたお方だ
（信）えっ？
そんな偉い人が呂不韋の配下に？
Someone that important is Lü Buwei's subordinate?
外交をつかさどる官の最高位
He has the highest positions of the diplomatic officials.
今は専ら 中華の東の果ての国 燕(えん)に
出向されていると聞いたが
I had heard he was devoting his time to head for the far Eastern tip of China, Yan, but...
（政）いつ戻った？
When did you return?
A few days ago, for an engagement.
（蔡沢）先日 所用にて
すぐに また東に戻りまする
I will be returning to the East soon.
You worry me...
（政）苦労をかける
くれぐれも体に気をつけよ
Please make sure to take care of yourself.
（蔡沢）ヒッヒッ…
お心遣い 感謝いたしまする
I thank you for the sympathy.
（信）何だ？ あのじいさん
やけに親しげだな　ホントに敵か？
What's with that old man?
He's being awfully endearing. Is he really an enemy?
（壁）蔡沢さまは
王を軽んずる方ではない　ただ…
Lord Cai Ou is not someone who looks down on the king, but...
Cai Ou
*One of Lü Buwei's Four Pillars (close aids)
（蔡沢）早(は)よう大きゅう
なりなされ 大王
I hope you grow up soon, my king.
この蔡沢は…
I, Cai Ou,
only serve the strong.
強き者にのみ
お仕えいたしまするぞ
（蔡沢）ヒヒヒッ… では 失礼
Well then, excuse me.
おぬしも
早く帰りたいんじゃろう？ 蒙武(もうぶ)
You wish to return soon as well, don't you, Meng Wu?
It is written all over your face.
そう顔に書いてあるぞい
（蒙武）当然だ　俺とて
こんな茶番につきあってる暇はない
Of course! I do not have time to be dealing with a farce such as this!
（李斯(りし)）口を慎め 蒙武
Watch your tongue, Meng Wu!
Li Si
*One of Lü Buwei's Four Pillars (close aids)
（李斯）
蔡沢さまは ともかく
For Lord Cai Ou it is a different story, but you do not have the qualifications to speak the word "farce" here!
貴様に〝茶番〞などと
言う資格はない
Meng Wu
*One of Lü Buwei's Four Pillars (close aids)
貴様こそ 誰に―
And who do you think you're speaking to, Li Si?!
口を聞いているつもりだ
李斯！
ここ王宮は 政(まつりごと)の場だ
This Royal Palace is a place of governing.
そして 政とは 貴様ごときに
理解できるようなものではない
And governing is something a man like you cannot possibly understand.
全ての言葉に 深い意味があるのだ
All words contain a deep meaning.
（蒙武）勝手にしろ
俺が求めるものは戦場にしかない
Do what you want! The only thing I desire is on the battlefield!
（李斯）ほう… 力任せに
突き進むしか能のない貴様が―
Oh? What do you, someone with no talent, that relies only on power to push themselves forward,
戦場に何を求めるというのだ？
seek on the battlefield?
武の証明だ
（李斯）うん？
Proof of valor.
この蒙武こそ 中華最強！
I, Meng Wu, am the strongest in all of China!
その証明以外 一切の興味なし！
I haven't the least bit of interest in anything but proof of that!
“中華最強”…
Strongest... in all of China...!
“中華最強”か…
じゃが 妙じゃのぅ
Strongest in all of China, eh...?
But it's odd.
貴様より強い男が
そこに１人おるぞい
I do believe there's one man stronger than you right there.
Isn't that right, Changpinjun?
なあ？ 昌平君(しょうへいくん)
Changpinjun
*One of Lü Buwei's Four Pillars (close aids)
This has gone beyond joking, Lord Cai Ou.
（昌平君）冗談が
過ぎますぞ 蔡沢どの
ヒッヒッ…
これは失敬　今のは なしの方向で
How rude of me...
Let us forget that last statement.
（呂不韋）ハハハハッ…
いいかげんにせぬか 皆の者
Enough jesting, all of you.
大王の前で
ペラペラと おしゃべりしおって
I do believe all this idle chat in front of the king
おかげで
足が しびれてしもうたではないか
has started to make my legs numb.
大王さま… どうか
配下のご無礼をお許しください
Your highness, I beg you forgive the rudeness of my subordinates.
これも 彼らが 揺るぎなき己の道を
歩んでおればこそ
This is because they so firmly walk their own paths.
そして これこそが 本日
お目通りを願ったいまひとつの目的
And one other matter for which I have sought this audience with you today.
竭たちの反乱が平定された今
With the rebellion of Jie and the others suppressed...
我が配下が粛々と この秦国を治め
守ってまいりますゆえ
my subordinates will quietly govern and protect this State of Qin.
どうぞ ご安心を
So please, rest at ease!
（政）よろしく頼む
I trust that you will.
では 大王さま…
Well then, your highness,
これにて！
I take my leave!
（蔡沢）楽しそうじゃのぅ 丞相
（呂不韋）そう見えますかな？
This seems entertaining, chancellor.
Did it appear so?
大王さまは 内心―
Internally, the king is surely in a furious rage.
はらわたが煮えくり返るような
思いをしておられたろうが
それを面(おもて)に表さなんだ
若いのに なかなか大したものじゃ
It showed on his face.
He may be young, but he is still quite a man.
We've found an opponent that seems to be worth playing with...
“遊びがいのありそうな相手が
見つかった”
そう思うとるんじゃろう？
Don't you think so?
一国の王をつかまえて
遊び相手とは…
Seizing the king of a country to play with him...
恐ろしいことをおっしゃる
フフフッ…
You speak of something quite tremendous.
（昌文君）大王さま おやめを！
おケガをなさいますぞ！
Your highness, please stop!
You'll hurt yourself!
Hey.
（信）おい
ちょっと外の空気吸おうぜ
Let's go get a breath of fresh air.
（信）驚いたなぁ
お前も物に当たることあるんだな
That surprised me.
You hit things sometimes, too, huh?
（政）これが当たらずにいられるか
Do you think I could stand not to?!
In front of an enemy that wants to kill you,
自分の命を狙ってる相手を前に
何も言えなかったもんな お前
you couldn't even say anything.
ハハハッ… 惨敗だ 惨敗
You really lost that one! Pretty crushingly!
（政）
フン… おかしければ笑うがいい
これが現実だ
If you think it's funny, then go ahead, laugh.
This is reality.
でっけえ敵だな
That's one huge enemy!
（政）法をつかさどる李斯
Governor of law, Li Shi.
軍事をつかさどる昌平君と蒙武
Governors of the armies, Changpinjun and Meng Wu.
外交 および
そのほか全般の相談役 蔡沢
Diplomacy and general advisor, Cai Ou.
“四柱(しちゅう)”と呼ばれるこの４人が
呂不韋陣営の大きな柱だ
These four, known as the Four Pillars,
are great pillars supporting the Lü Buwei faction.
（信）
４人とも ただ者じゃないってのは
見て分かったぜ
Even though there were just four, they were no ordinary people.
I could tell just by lookin' at them.
でも 本当にやべえのは あいつだ
（貂）うん？
But the really dangerous guy was him!
（政）そう　四柱をはじめ
並みいる配下を束ねる男…
Yes... The man who started the Four Pillars and tied together the subordinates around him...
Chancellor Lü Buwei!
丞相 呂不韋
12～13年前まで
呂不韋は ただの他国の商人だった
Until 12 or 13 years ago, Lü Buwei was just an ordinary foreign merchant.
Foreign merchant?
他国の商人？ それが
なんで今 秦国の丞相なんだ？
Then why's he a general of the State of Qin now?
（政）
呂不韋は 王位継承の候補にすら
入ってなかった俺の父のために―
When my father wasn't even in contention to inherit the throne,
Lü Buwei spent his money on him.
財をはたいた
呂不韋の金と策により
父は秦国の王となり
With Lü Buwei's money and planning, my father became the king of the State of Qin.
And as a reward, he gave Lü Buwei the seat of chancellor.
その褒美として
呂不韋は 丞相の席を与えられた
To put it simply, those were the circumstances that led to him becoming chancellor.
端的に言えば
これが ヤツが丞相になった経緯だ
（政）だが 金や小細工だけで―
But merely money and shrewdness are not enough to rise
庶民から 一国の権力者にまで
駆け上がることなどできぬ
from commoner to one of the most powerful people in a country.
それは 将軍を目指すお前なら
よく分かるはずだ 信
Aiming to become a general as you are, I'm sure you understand, Xin.
Yeah. That old man's the real deal.
ああ　あのおっさんは本物だ
（政）俺も含めて
両陣営の力の差は大きい
Even including me, the difference in power between the two factions is too great.
おい！ まさか もう―
Hey! Don't tell me you're ready to give up the fight already, Zheng?
戦意喪失してんじゃ
ねえだろうな？ 政
バカを言え　相手にとって
不足はないと言ってるんだ
Don't be foolish.
I'm saying that he is a worthy adversary!
（信）少しは気が晴れたか？
（政）お前に気を遣われるとはな
So you've cleared your head a bit, huh?
Having you be concerned for me...
is as bad as it gets.
最悪だ
（信）ああ？
（信）お前 ここで言ったよな？
You told me here, right?
Once I reach age 20 and come of age, I'll definitely wrench power away from Lü Shi.
二十歳になり 加冠すれば
必ず 呂氏から権力を剥ぎ取る
そして…
And...
I will depart for China!
俺は中華に出る
（信）そっか
Is that right?
信 そのときまでには
必ず上ってこい
Xin, until that time comes, be sure to rise up to meet me.
（信）おう
Right.
負けらんねえぞ 政
I ain't gonna lose, Zheng.
（政）フッ… さっきから
俺のことばかり言っているが
We've been talking only about me for a while now,
but you need to get started soon.
お前も そろそろ始まるぞ
（信）“始まる”？ 何が？
Started...? With what?
次の戦だ
With the next war.
ハッ…
（信）本当か？ 政
Really, Zheng?!
Right now, if you include Qin, China is broken into seven states.
いま 中華は 我が秦国を含めて
７つの国がひしめき
It's in a state of ruthless competition.
しのぎを削っている状況だ
火種は いくらでもある
There are many live coals ready to start fires...
現に 国境の近くで 不審な動きを
している国があるとも聞く
I have also heard that a state has been making some suspicious movements near our state borders.
At this time, it would not be odd to raise the flames of war.
この瞬間に 戦の火の手が
上がっても 何の不思議もない
じゃ 帰っか！ 行くぞ 貂！
Okay, let's head back!
C'mon, Diao!
えっ？ でも 俺…
But I...
（貂）まだ金もらってねえ！
still haven't gotten my money!
G-Good work.
（幸）ご… ご苦労さまです
（信）ウイッス！
Thanks!
よし！ 肩も治った！
準備は もうできてるぜ！
Okay! My shoulder's back to normal, too!
And I'm ready to go!
（信）
えっと… 何て書いてあんだ？
Uh... What's written there?
読めねえのかよ？ 読んでやるよ
Can't you read?
I can.
ほう…
そんで 何て書いてあんだよ？
Oh? So what's written there?
分かりやすく言うとだな
To make it easy to understand...
（貂）“隣の魏国(ぎこく)を攻めるから
歩兵を募集する”ってさ
"The neighboring state, Wei, is attacking. So we're recruiting soldiers."
What'd you just say, Diao?!
今 何つった？ 貂
Diao!
貂！
You must be glad, Xin!
良かったな 信　いよいよ初陣だ
You'll finally go on your first campaign!
えっ？ ウワッ！
All riiiiight!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
～♪
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
（信）
これが天下の大将軍への第１歩だ！
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）空気が重い
だが 魂が燃える　本物の戦だ
I won't cry
次回 “初陣”
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
This is...
my first step to becoming the greatest general under the heavens!
The atmosphere is heavy...
but the souls burn!
First Campaign
It's a real war!
End
First Campaign
Next time.